# Colette M. Borden Berry | Résumé

Experienced and dedicated **Jewelry Cataloguer** who delivers clean and meticulously proofed work under tight deadlines. Possesses extensive knowledge of makers, maker's marks, and gemology; some **Specialist** appraisal experience. Demonstrates a positive attitude, communicates well, learns quickly, and seeks challenges.

## **Experience**

Sotheby's Geneva, Switzerland

Head of Catalogue Production/Cataloguer

2011-present

Responsibilities include: cataloguing, layout, and proofing of Geneva jewelry sale catalogues; pre-sale public exhibitions; producing and providing condition reports; liaising with clients and the Marketing and Press departments; proofing and approving outgoing material; inventory checks; releases; supporting appraisals as needed.

- Produced catalogues for several of the highest ever grossing jewelry auctions in history, including the May 2014
   'Magnificent Jewels and Noble Jewels' sale, which set seven world auction records and totaled a historic \$141.5 million
- Organization of pre-sale public exhibitions, including: selection of visuals/layout; supervision of more than 30 temporary employees; supervision of client services; primary contact for security and specialists
- o Streamlined cataloguing in European offices (London, Milan, Geneva) to implement consistent style, vocabulary, and photography

Complesso del Vittoriano Rome, Italy

Exhibition Guide

March-June 2009

Led private tours in English and Italian of the 'Giotto e il Trecento' exhibit, hailed as one of Italy's most important exhibitions of the year

Instituto Marymount Rome, Italy

Visual Arts Educator

January-June 2009

Responsible for lesson planning, teaching, and field trips for bilingual children

Peggy Guggenheim Collection

Venice, Italy

Intern

September-November 2008

Led public and private tours of the collection in French, Italian, and English. Assisted with daily operations, special events, translations, and proofing

## Studio Art Center International (SACI)

Florence, Italy

Professor's Assistant

September 2007-June 2008

Tutored and graded undergraduate courses in late Medieval through Baroque Art History. Led visits of museums and major civic/religious monuments in various Italian cities

Altesino Montalcino, Italy

Winery Guide

June-September 2007

Conducted tastings and visits of a winery featured numerous times in 'Wine Spectator' and 'Vintage' for producing one of the 'Top 100 Wines of the Year'

Tiffany & Co. Boston, MA

Customer Service Associate

December 2006-June 2007

Responsible for small repairs, alterations, cleaning, and polishing of jewelry at Tiffany & Co.'s third most profitable location worldwide for 2006

The Phillips Collection

Washington, D.C.

Intern

September-December 2005

Assisted Marketing & Communications Manager

# **Education**

#### Gemological Institute of America (GIA)

Distance Education

Graduate Colored Stones Diploma

2011-Present

Relevant coursework:

o Diamond Essentials, Colored Stones Essentials, Colored Stones, Colored Stone Grading Lab (on-campus, London), Gem Identification Lab (on-campus, New York), Gem Identification (currently enrolled, final class for diploma)

#### University of Geneva

Geneva, Switzerland

M.A., Art History

2009-2011

Thesis graded 6/6

Une époque dans tous ses éclats: Les bijoux produits à Paris au 16ème siècle
[An Era in all its Splendor: Jewels Produced in 16th Century Paris]
 A study of the production and function of Renaissance jewelry in France, specifically Paris, together with a catalogue of approximately 100 jewels identified as authentic following the discovery of 19th century reproductions.

#### **American University**

Washington, D.C.

B.A., Art History

2002-2006

o Dean's List

### Skills

Technical: SAP, Microsoft Office Suite, LATEX

Languages: English and French (First Language), Italian (Conversational)

**Professional**: Cataloguing, Catalogue Production, Condition Reports, Gem Identification, Appraisals Connoisseurship, Research, Planning/Coordinating Exhibitions, Marketing, Client Development